<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
 <forms>
  <collectionName>PhenX Protocols - 2.2</collectionName>
  <collectionDescription>Load PhenX PX020304,PX020303</collectionDescription>
        <form>
    <context>PhenX</context>
    <createdBy>dwarzel</createdBy>
    <dateCreated>2016-11-02T13:05:04</dateCreated>
    <longName>PhenX  Body Composition Subscapular Skinfold Thickness - PX020304</longName>
    <changeNote>Uploaded via FormLoader</changeNote>
    <preferredDefinition>Measurement of the study subject subcutaneous fat mass using calipers to measure skinfold thickness at the subscapular.	
	Skinfold thicknesses may also be measured at a number of other sites, including the midaxillary, pectoral, abdominal, anterior thigh, suprapatellar, medial calf, biceps, and forearm sites. If these latter sites are of interest, definitions and protocols are available in manuals that describe anthropometric measurements.</preferredDefinition>
    <cadsrRAI>2.16.840.1.113883.3.26.2</cadsrRAI>
    <version>1</version>
    <workflowStatusName>DRAFT NEW</workflowStatusName>
    <type>CRF</type>    
     <module>
      <displayOrder>0</displayOrder>
      <maximumModuleRepeat>0</maximumModuleRepeat>
      <createdBy>panh</createdBy>
      <dateCreated>2016-11-02T13:05:04</dateCreated>
      <longName>N/A</longName>
      <preferredDefinition>No definition</preferredDefinition>
      <question>
        <isDerived>false</isDerived>
        <displayOrder>0</displayOrder>
        <dateCreated>2016-11-02T13:05:04</dateCreated>
         <questionText>Subscapular Skinfold: The subscapular skinfold is measured at the inferior angle of the right scapula. Instructions for performing the subscapular skinfold measure are provided below:1. Position the participant: Similar to the triceps skinfold measure, turn the participant so that you stand behind his or her right side. Have the participant stand upright with weight evenly distributed on both feet, shoulders relaxed, and arms hanging loosely at the sides.2. Mark the measurement site: Tell the participant that you are going to open the gown in the back and mark the skin with the cosmetic pencil. Open the back of the gown and palpate for the inferior angle, or triangle portion, of the right scapula (Exhibit 6). Using the cosmetic pencil, mark a cross (X) on the inferior angle (Exhibit 7). Make the first line at 45 to the spine and cross this with a line that bisects the inferior angle of the scapula.3. Grasp the skinfold: Using your thumb and index finger, grasp a fold so that the index finger remains situated roughly 2.0 cm above and medial to the inferior angle of the scapula.Due to tightness in this area of the back on many participants, obtaining this skinfold measure can be a challenge. In the cases where you experience difficulty separating the subscapular skinfold from the underlying tissue, begin grasping the fold with the thumb and index finger spread wide.4. Position the caliper: Continue to hold the skinfold in place. With the other hand, set the top jaw of the caliper on the "+" mark. This differs from the triceps skinfold procedure in which the mark is centered between the caliper tips. Position the tips of the caliper jaws over the complete skinfold perpendicular to the length of the fold and roughly 2.0 cm lateral to the fingers (Exhibit 8).5. Take the measurement: Continue to hold the skinfold in place and release the caliper handle to exert full tension on the skinfold...TRUNCATED</questionText>     
         <isEditable>No</isEditable>
        <isMandatory>No</isMandatory>
        <multiValue>No</multiValue>
       </question>
       <question>
        <isDerived>false</isDerived>
        <displayOrder>1</displayOrder>
        <dateCreated>2016-11-02T13:05:04</dateCreated>
        <questionText>Have the study staff undergone any training or retraining in anthropometric data collection?</questionText>        
        <isEditable>No</isEditable>
        <isMandatory>No</isMandatory>
        <multiValue>No</multiValue>
                 <validValue>
          <displayOrder>0</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE</value>
          <meaningText>Yes</meaningText>
         </validValue>
         <validValue>
          <displayOrder>1</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE_1</value>
          <meaningText>No</meaningText>
         </validValue>
               </question>
       <question>
        <isDerived>false</isDerived>
        <displayOrder>2</displayOrder>
        <dateCreated>2016-11-02T13:05:04</dateCreated>
        <questionText>Will duplicate measurements be taken?</questionText>        
        <isEditable>No</isEditable>
        <isMandatory>No</isMandatory>
        <multiValue>No</multiValue>
                 <validValue>
          <displayOrder>0</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE</value>
          <meaningText>Yes</meaningText>
         </validValue>
         <validValue>
          <displayOrder>1</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE_1</value>
          <meaningText>No</meaningText>
         </validValue>
               </question>
       <question>
        <isDerived>false</isDerived>
        <displayOrder>3</displayOrder>
        <dateCreated>2016-11-02T13:05:04</dateCreated>
        <questionText>Is the team adequately staffed so that more than one person is available for proper collection of measurements where required?</questionText>
                <isEditable>No</isEditable>
        <isMandatory>No</isMandatory>
        <multiValue>No</multiValue>
                 <validValue>
          <displayOrder>0</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE</value>
          <meaningText>Yes</meaningText>
         </validValue>
         <validValue>
          <displayOrder>1</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE_1</value>
          <meaningText>No</meaningText>
         </validValue>
               </question>
       <question>
        <isDerived>false</isDerived>
        <displayOrder>4</displayOrder>
        <dateCreated>2016-11-02T13:05:04</dateCreated>
        <questionText>Has the staff been properly trained to acquire an accurate recording of the protocols and measurements units of data collection?</questionText>
               <isEditable>No</isEditable>
        <isMandatory>No</isMandatory>
        <multiValue>No</multiValue>
                 <validValue>
          <displayOrder>0</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE</value>
          <meaningText>Yes</meaningText>
         </validValue>
         <validValue>
          <displayOrder>1</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE_1</value>
          <meaningText>No</meaningText>
         </validValue>
               </question>
       <question>
        <isDerived>false</isDerived>
        <displayOrder>5</displayOrder>
        <dateCreated>2016-11-02T13:05:04</dateCreated>
        <questionText>Has the staff been properly trained in the use of and have access to required and properly calibrated equipment?</questionText>
                <isEditable>No</isEditable>
        <isMandatory>No</isMandatory>
        <multiValue>No</multiValue>
                 <validValue>
          <displayOrder>0</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE</value>
          <meaningText>Yes</meaningText>
         </validValue>
         <validValue>
          <displayOrder>1</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE_1</value>
          <meaningText>No</meaningText>
         </validValue>
               </question>
       <question>
        <isDerived>false</isDerived>
        <displayOrder>6</displayOrder>
        <dateCreated>2016-11-02T13:05:04</dateCreated>
        <questionText>Was the participant instructed to stand upright with weight evenly distributed on both feet, shoulders relaxed, and arms hanging loosely at the sides?</questionText>
        
        <isEditable>No</isEditable>
        <isMandatory>No</isMandatory>
        <multiValue>No</multiValue>
                 <validValue>
          <displayOrder>0</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE</value>
          <meaningText>Yes</meaningText>
         </validValue>
         <validValue>
          <displayOrder>1</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE_1</value>
          <meaningText>No</meaningText>
         </validValue>
               </question>
       <question>
        <isDerived>false</isDerived>
        <displayOrder>7</displayOrder>
        <dateCreated>2016-11-02T13:05:04</dateCreated>
        <questionText>Using a cosmetic pencil, was a cross (X) marked on the inferior angle, or triangle portion, of the subject's right scapula?</questionText>
        
        <isEditable>No</isEditable>
        <isMandatory>No</isMandatory>
        <multiValue>No</multiValue>
                 <validValue>
          <displayOrder>0</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE</value>
          <meaningText>Yes</meaningText>
         </validValue>
         <validValue>
          <displayOrder>1</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE_1</value>
          <meaningText>No</meaningText>
         </validValue>
               </question>
       <question>
        <isDerived>false</isDerived>
        <displayOrder>8</displayOrder>
        <dateCreated>2016-11-02T13:05:04</dateCreated>
        <questionText>Was a fold of skin grasped using the thumb and index finger roughly 2.0 cm above and medial to the inferior angle of the scapula?</questionText>
         <isEditable>No</isEditable>
        <isMandatory>No</isMandatory>
        <multiValue>No</multiValue>
                 <validValue>
          <displayOrder>0</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE</value>
          <meaningText>Yes</meaningText>
         </validValue>
         <validValue>
          <displayOrder>1</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE_1</value>
          <meaningText>No</meaningText>
         </validValue>
               </question>
       <question>
        <isDerived>false</isDerived>
        <displayOrder>9</displayOrder>
        <dateCreated>2016-11-02T13:05:04</dateCreated>
        <questionText>While holding the skinfold, were the tips of the caliper jaws positions over the complete skinfold perpendicular to the length of the fold, roughly 2.0 cm lateral to the fingers?</questionText>
        
        <isEditable>No</isEditable>
        <isMandatory>No</isMandatory>
        <multiValue>No</multiValue>
                 <validValue>
          <displayOrder>0</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE</value>
          <meaningText>Yes</meaningText>
         </validValue>
         <validValue>
          <displayOrder>1</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE_1</value>
          <meaningText>No</meaningText>
         </validValue>
               </question>
       <question>
        <isDerived>false</isDerived>
        <displayOrder>10</displayOrder>
        <dateCreated>2016-11-02T13:05:04</dateCreated>
        <questionText>When the caliper handle was released to exert full tension of the skinfold, did the staff member wait 3 seconds for the needle on the caliper dial to settle before taking a measurement?</questionText>
         <isEditable>No</isEditable>
        <isMandatory>No</isMandatory>
        <multiValue>No</multiValue>
                 <validValue>
          <displayOrder>0</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE</value>
          <meaningText>Yes</meaningText>
         </validValue>
         <validValue>
          <displayOrder>1</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE_1</value>
          <meaningText>No</meaningText>
         </validValue>
               </question>
       <question>
        <isDerived>false</isDerived>
        <displayOrder>11</displayOrder>
        <dateCreated>2016-11-02T13:05:04</dateCreated>
        <questionText>What was the measurement of the thickness of the skinfold to the nearest 0.2 mm?</questionText>
         <isEditable>No</isEditable>
        <isMandatory>No</isMandatory>
        <multiValue>No</multiValue>
               </question>
           </module>
        <protocol>
     <protocolID>PX020304</protocolID>
     <longName>Body Composition - Subscapular Skinfold Thickness</longName>
     <context>PhenX</context>
     <shortName>PX020304</shortName>
     <preferredDefinition>Measurement of the study subject subcutaneous fat mass using calipers to measure skinfold thickness at the subscapular. Skinfold thicknesses may also be measured at a number of other sites, including the midaxillary, pectoral, abdominal, anterior thigh, suprapatellar, medial calf, biceps, and forearm sites. If these latter sites are of interest, definitions and protocols are available in manuals that describe anthropometric measurements.</preferredDefinition>
    </protocol>
   </form>
    <form>
    <context>PhenX</context>
    <createdBy>dwarzel</createdBy>
    <dateCreated>2016-11-02T13:05:04</dateCreated>
    <longName>PhenX  Body Composition Triceps Skinfold Thickness - PX020303</longName>
    <changeNote>Uploaded via FormLoader</changeNote>
    <preferredDefinition>Measurement of the study subject subcutaneous fat mass using calipers to measure skinfold thickness over the triceps muscle. Skinfold thicknesses may also be measured at the number of other sites, including the midaxillary, pectoral, abdominal, anterior thigh, suprapatellar, medical calf, biceps, and forearm sites. If these latter sites are of interest, definitions and protocols are available in manuals that describe anthropometric measurements.</preferredDefinition>
    <cadsrRAI>2.16.840.1.113883.3.26.2</cadsrRAI>
    <version>1</version>
    <workflowStatusName>DRAFT NEW</workflowStatusName>
    <type>CRF</type>
    
     <module>
      <displayOrder>0</displayOrder>
      <maximumModuleRepeat>0</maximumModuleRepeat>
      <createdBy>panh</createdBy>
      <dateCreated>2016-11-02T13:05:04</dateCreated>
      <longName>N/A</longName>
      <preferredDefinition>No definition</preferredDefinition>
             <question>
        <isDerived>false</isDerived>
        <displayOrder>0</displayOrder>
        <dateCreated>2016-11-02T13:05:04</dateCreated>
        <questionText>Triceps Skinfold: The triceps skinfold is measured at the midpoint of the upper arm. The procedures for making this mark are explained in Upper Arm Length. Follow the procedures after that to perform the triceps skinfold measure.Upper Arm Length:1. Position the participant: Direct the participant to turn away from you. Ask him or her to stand upright with weight evenly distributed on both feet, the right arm bent 90 at the elbow, and the right palm facing up. Demonstrate the correct position if necessary.2. Mark the measurement site: Locate the end of the spine of the right scapula by following the scapula out to the arm until it makes a sharp Vturn to the front of the body. Using the cosmetic pencil, make a horizontal line on the uppermost edge of the posterior border of the spine extending from the acromion process (see Exhibit 1).3. Take the measurement: Hold the zero end of the measuring tape at this mark and extend the tape down the posterior surface of the arm to the tip of the olecranon process, the bony part of the midelbow (Exhibit 2). Take the measurement to the nearest 0.1 cm. IMPORTANT: The tape must be centered on the posterior surface of the arm. Exhibit 2 shows the correct placement of the measuring tape centered on the posterior surface of the arm, whereas Exhibit 3 shows the measuring tape placed incorrectly.4. Divide the measure in half to calculate the midpoint of the measured length. Make a horizontal mark at the midpoint and cross this mark with a perpendicular line (Exhibit 4). IMPORTANT: The vertical line must be centered on the posterior surface of the arm.5. After marking the arm, the participant can relax his or her arm</questionText>
        <instruction/>
        <isEditable>No</isEditable>
        <isMandatory>No</isMandatory>
        <multiValue>No</multiValue>
               </question>
       <question>
        <isDerived>false</isDerived>
        <displayOrder>1</displayOrder>
        <dateCreated>2016-11-02T13:05:04</dateCreated>
        <questionText>1. Position the participant: Ask the participant to turn so that you stand behind his or her right side. Have the participant stand upright with weight evenly distributed on both feet, the shoulders relaxed, and the arms hanging loosely at the sides. Flexing or tightening the arm muscles when the measurement is made will yield an inaccurate measurement.2. Grasp the skinfold: Using your thumb and index finger, grasp a fold of skin and subcutaneous adipose tissue approximately 2.0 cm above the midarm circumference mark. If you have difficulty separating the skinfold from the triceps muscle, start at the elbow where the tissue tends to be looser and work your way up to the mark. Ensure that the skinfold consists of a double thickness and sits parallel to the long axis of the arm.3. Position the caliper: Holding the skinfold 2.0 cm above the ircumference mark, place the tips of the caliper jaws over the complete skinfold. Ensure that the mark remains centered between the tips and that the jaws sit perpendicular to the length of the skinfold. Exhibit 5 shows the correct placement of the caliper for this measurement.4. Take the measurement: Continue to hold the skinfold in place and release the caliper handle to exert full tension on the skinfold. Wait 3 seconds for the needle on the caliper dial to settle on an accurate measurement. Read the thickness to the nearest 0.2 mm.5. Record the result. Remove the caliper jaws first and then release the skinfold</questionText>
        <instruction/>
        <isEditable>No</isEditable>
        <isMandatory>No</isMandatory>
        <multiValue>No</multiValue>
               </question>
       <question>
        <isDerived>false</isDerived>
        <displayOrder>2</displayOrder>
        <dateCreated>2016-11-02T13:05:04</dateCreated>
        <questionText>Have the study staff undergone any training or retraining in anthropometric data collection?</questionText>
        <instruction/>
        <isEditable>No</isEditable>
        <isMandatory>No</isMandatory>
        <multiValue>No</multiValue>
                 <validValue>
          <displayOrder>0</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE</value>
          <meaningText>Yes</meaningText>
         </validValue>
         <validValue>
          <displayOrder>1</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE_1</value>
          <meaningText>No</meaningText>
         </validValue>
               </question>
       <question>
        <isDerived>false</isDerived>
        <displayOrder>3</displayOrder>
        <dateCreated>2016-11-02T13:05:04</dateCreated>
        <questionText>Will duplicate measurements be taken?</questionText>
        <instruction/>
        <isEditable>No</isEditable>
        <isMandatory>No</isMandatory>
        <multiValue>No</multiValue>
                 <validValue>
          <displayOrder>0</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE</value>
          <meaningText>Yes</meaningText>
         </validValue>
         <validValue>
          <displayOrder>1</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE_1</value>
          <meaningText>No</meaningText>
         </validValue>
               </question>
       <question>
        <isDerived>false</isDerived>
        <displayOrder>4</displayOrder>
        <dateCreated>2016-11-02T13:05:04</dateCreated>
        <questionText>Is the team adequately staffed so that more than one person is available for proper collection of measurements where required?</questionText>
        <instruction/>
        <isEditable>No</isEditable>
        <isMandatory>No</isMandatory>
        <multiValue>No</multiValue>
                 <validValue>
          <displayOrder>0</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE</value>
          <meaningText>Yes</meaningText>
         </validValue>
         <validValue>
          <displayOrder>1</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE_1</value>
          <meaningText>No</meaningText>
         </validValue>
               </question>
       <question>
        <isDerived>false</isDerived>
        <displayOrder>5</displayOrder>
        <dateCreated>2016-11-02T13:05:04</dateCreated>
        <questionText>Has the staff been properly trained to acquire an accurate recording of the protocols and measurements units of data collection?</questionText>
        <instruction/>
        <isEditable>No</isEditable>
        <isMandatory>No</isMandatory>
        <multiValue>No</multiValue>
                 <validValue>
          <displayOrder>0</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE</value>
          <meaningText>Yes</meaningText>
         </validValue>
         <validValue>
          <displayOrder>1</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE_1</value>
          <meaningText>No</meaningText>
         </validValue>
               </question>
       <question>
        <isDerived>false</isDerived>
        <displayOrder>6</displayOrder>
        <dateCreated>2016-11-02T13:05:04</dateCreated>
        <questionText>Has the staff been properly trained in the use of and have access to required and properly calibrated equipment?</questionText>
        <instruction/>
        <isEditable>No</isEditable>
        <isMandatory>No</isMandatory>
        <multiValue>No</multiValue>
                 <validValue>
          <displayOrder>0</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE</value>
          <meaningText>Yes</meaningText>
         </validValue>
         <validValue>
          <displayOrder>1</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE_1</value>
          <meaningText>No</meaningText>
         </validValue>
               </question>
       <question>
        <isDerived>false</isDerived>
        <displayOrder>7</displayOrder>
        <dateCreated>2016-11-02T13:05:04</dateCreated>
        <questionText>Was the participant instructed to stand upright with weight evenly distributed on both feet, right arm bent 90 degrees at the elbow, and the right palm facing up?</questionText>
        <instruction/>
        <isEditable>No</isEditable>
        <isMandatory>No</isMandatory>
        <multiValue>No</multiValue>
                 <validValue>
          <displayOrder>0</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE</value>
          <meaningText>Yes</meaningText>
         </validValue>
         <validValue>
          <displayOrder>1</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE_1</value>
          <meaningText>No</meaningText>
         </validValue>
               </question>
       <question>
        <isDerived>false</isDerived>
        <displayOrder>8</displayOrder>
        <dateCreated>2016-11-02T13:05:04</dateCreated>
        <questionText>After locating the end of the spine of the right scapula by following the scapula out to the arm until it makes a sharp Vturn to the front of the body, using a cosmetic pencil, was a horizontal line made at the uppermost edge of the posterior border of the spine extending from the acromion process (see exhibit 1)?</questionText>
        <instruction/>
        <isEditable>No</isEditable>
        <isMandatory>No</isMandatory>
        <multiValue>No</multiValue>
                 <validValue>
          <displayOrder>0</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE</value>
          <meaningText>Yes</meaningText>
         </validValue>
         <validValue>
          <displayOrder>1</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE_1</value>
          <meaningText>No</meaningText>
         </validValue>
               </question>
       <question>
        <isDerived>false</isDerived>
        <displayOrder>9</displayOrder>
        <dateCreated>2016-11-02T13:05:04</dateCreated>
        <questionText>Holding the zero end of the measuring tape at the horizontal line mark, was a measurement taken by extending the tape down the posterior surface of the arm to the tip of the olecranon process (the bony part of the elbow, exhibit 2)?</questionText>
        <instruction/>
        <isEditable>No</isEditable>
        <isMandatory>No</isMandatory>
        <multiValue>No</multiValue>
                 <validValue>
          <displayOrder>0</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE</value>
          <meaningText>Yes</meaningText>
         </validValue>
         <validValue>
          <displayOrder>1</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE_1</value>
          <meaningText>No</meaningText>
         </validValue>
               </question>
       <question>
        <isDerived>false</isDerived>
        <displayOrder>10</displayOrder>
        <dateCreated>2016-11-02T13:05:04</dateCreated>
        <questionText>What was the measurement, to the nearest 0.1 cm?</questionText>
        <instruction/>
        <isEditable>No</isEditable>
        <isMandatory>No</isMandatory>
        <multiValue>No</multiValue>
               </question>
       <question>
        <isDerived>false</isDerived>
        <displayOrder>11</displayOrder>
        <dateCreated>2016-11-02T13:05:04</dateCreated>
        <questionText>After dividing the taken measurement in half, was a horizontal mark made at the midpoint?</questionText>
        <instruction/>
        <isEditable>No</isEditable>
        <isMandatory>No</isMandatory>
        <multiValue>No</multiValue>
                 <validValue>
          <displayOrder>0</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE</value>
          <meaningText>Yes</meaningText>
         </validValue>
         <validValue>
          <displayOrder>1</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE_1</value>
          <meaningText>No</meaningText>
         </validValue>
               </question>
       <question>
        <isDerived>false</isDerived>
        <displayOrder>12</displayOrder>
        <dateCreated>2016-11-02T13:05:04</dateCreated>
        <questionText>Was the participant instructed to stand upright with weight evenly distributed on both feet, shoulders relaxed, and arms hanging loosely at the sides?</questionText>
        <instruction/>
        <isEditable>No</isEditable>
        <isMandatory>No</isMandatory>
        <multiValue>No</multiValue>
                 <validValue>
          <displayOrder>0</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE</value>
          <meaningText>Yes</meaningText>
         </validValue>
         <validValue>
          <displayOrder>1</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE_1</value>
          <meaningText>No</meaningText>
         </validValue>
               </question>
       <question>
        <isDerived>false</isDerived>
        <displayOrder>13</displayOrder>
        <dateCreated>2016-11-02T13:05:04</dateCreated>
        <questionText>Using the thumb and index finger, was the fold of skin and subcutaneous adipose tissue grasped approximately 2.0 cm above the midarm circumference mark?</questionText>
        <instruction/>
        <isEditable>No</isEditable>
        <isMandatory>No</isMandatory>
        <multiValue>No</multiValue>
                 <validValue>
          <displayOrder>0</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE</value>
          <meaningText>Yes</meaningText>
         </validValue>
         <validValue>
          <displayOrder>1</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE_1</value>
          <meaningText>No</meaningText>
         </validValue>
               </question>
       <question>
        <isDerived>false</isDerived>
        <displayOrder>14</displayOrder>
        <dateCreated>2016-11-02T13:05:04</dateCreated>
        <questionText>While holding the skinfold 2.0 cm above the circumference mark, were the tips of the calipers placed over the complete skinfold?</questionText>
        <instruction/>
        <isEditable>No</isEditable>
        <isMandatory>No</isMandatory>
        <multiValue>No</multiValue>
                 <validValue>
          <displayOrder>0</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE</value>
          <meaningText>Yes</meaningText>
         </validValue>
         <validValue>
          <displayOrder>1</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE_1</value>
          <meaningText>No</meaningText>
         </validValue>
               </question>
       <question>
        <isDerived>false</isDerived>
        <displayOrder>15</displayOrder>
        <dateCreated>2016-11-02T13:05:04</dateCreated>
        <questionText>While holding the skinfold 2.0 cm above the circumference mark, was the caliper handle released to exert full tension on the skinfold for at least 3 seconds before a measurement was taken?</questionText>
        <instruction/>
        <isEditable>No</isEditable>
        <isMandatory>No</isMandatory>
        <multiValue>No</multiValue>
                 <validValue>
          <displayOrder>0</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE</value>
          <meaningText>Yes</meaningText>
         </validValue>
         <validValue>
          <displayOrder>1</displayOrder>
          <value>UNDEFINED_CODE_1</value>
          <meaningText>No</meaningText>
         </validValue>
               </question>
       <question>
        <isDerived>false</isDerived>
        <displayOrder>16</displayOrder>
        <dateCreated>2016-11-02T13:05:04</dateCreated>
        <questionText>What was the thickness of the skinfold to the nearest 0.2 mm?</questionText>
        <instruction/>
        <isEditable>No</isEditable>
        <isMandatory>No</isMandatory>
        <multiValue>No</multiValue>
               </question>
           </module>
        <protocol>
     <protocolID>PX020303</protocolID>
     <longName>Body Composition - Triceps Skinfold Thickness</longName>
     <context>PhenX</context>
     <shortName>PX020303</shortName>
     <preferredDefinition>Measurement of the study subject subcutaneous fat mass using calipers to measure skinfold thickness over the triceps muscle. Skinfold thicknesses may also be measured at the number of other sites, including the midaxillary, pectoral, abdominal, anterior thigh, suprapatellar, medical calf, biceps, and forearm sites. If these latter sites are of interest, definitions and protocols are available in manuals that describe anthropometric measurements.</preferredDefinition>
    </protocol>
   </form>
   </forms>